a critique of game b is that it's too
intangible too much talk not enough
action
and so you know you and i have had a
email conversation
over the last few days talking a little
bit about how to
describe the phasings of game a and what
some of the sub components
might be and i've kind of taken that a
little further and i'm going to be game
b
game b people right if i'm saying
something about the future it's game b
even if game a comes out of my mouth
and i'm going to i've expended extended
it to a whole bunch
of fairly tangible topics which i'm
going to run through
relatively rapidly so let's both try not
to
go down the rabbit hole of digressions
first
i think we both agreed that a reasonable
way to present the current state
we could call the pregame b world or
pre-b
for short where there doesn't actually
exist a whole
of a functioning game b group not even a
small one
but there's lots of things that people
are working on
to get ready for that first real step
and first you called this out in 2017
finding the others and that's starting
to happen right through twitter through
facebook through
all traveling around the country and
meeting to people and telling people
about game b
so let's let's let that one go because
that one seems to be happening and
though of course we'd encourage any of
our listeners
who think they would like to play game b
to reach out to these
connection points we talked about
earlier the game b group on facebook
and hashtag gameb on twitter and find
the
others but then the next one i know
you've spent a lot of time
thinking about this and also starting
applying it to your own life
is making changes in our lives to be
more game b
ready things like building courage and
optimism
integrity honesty and good faith
escaping the matrix
of status oriented consumerism and being
programmed by
psychologically astute mass and social
media
what are some other things in the in the
changing one's own life
that would you would say fit to this
pre-b world
hmm well three things pop up immediately
and they're
i don't know if they're related so one
is that i've noticed that
many people who come with a hey let's
get going
attitude have often not done
a lot of work on what i would call a
transparent
mind and so there's a uh what i would
call a naive
assumption that the paradigm that they
are very familiar with
whatever it happens to be is the right
paradigm
and what ends up happening of course is
that then they reshape the story of game
b into something that is a
like their paradigm so one of the things
is to actually take quite seriously
this notion of liminality even down to
the level of what i would call
trans-paradigmatic mind which is a a
real thing like that is not a trivial
capacity to be aware of the the
axiomatic assumptions that you are
bringing
into your sense making and to be able to
actually shift between different
paradigms as the the arena that you're
in changes that's one
two is building a capacity
for orienting your choices
on the basis of sensed meaningfulness
these two things are actually very
connected so
in game a we have we are we are very
very separated from developmentally and
and uh socially separated from our
capacity to orient our sense making on
the basis of the sense of meaningfulness
so for example we spend more time on
bullshit at work than with our kids
and so something is off and yet we don't
actually choose the thing that if we
were to spend real time on it as the
more meaningful
we rationalize and or just delude
ourselves or ignore
and that has to be broken like you
cannot do game b because that's the
primary piece of the capacity
is this primordial or prefigured
capacity in the human body to be able to
just notice
and be able to be aware of what is more
meaningful
than other things just to you like what
feels more meaningful just that
and being able to be like this really
concrete
self discipline to make sure you've got
shit straight
in order so if you're sacrificing that
if you're if you're either radically
unaware of what is most meaningful
fix that and then if you are noticing
that your choices aren't actually in
accordance with the values that you
think you hold
fix that and then notice what is the
capacity in you that actually allows you
to
sense what are the what are the values
that are going to orient towards
meaningfulness what are the values that
you hold
what's the sense that gives you that and
what's the sense that allows you to use
those values to actually
notice what would seem like really good
choices in
uh in front of you you have to relearn a
lot of machinery
that was pounded out of you largely by
both education
and the economy and being able to know
in yourself
what you actually care about and make
choices in the basis of what is actually
important to you
god that's so insane how hard that is
because
i find many many people are actually
running ideologies which is to say that
they
they substitute somebody else's
code somebody else's proposition for
what is important
in exchange for their own so instead of
listening to my own sensing of what i
actually care about
i actually override myself in favor of
some particular ideology that has
somehow been
been able to impose itself on me as
being more important
and and therefore more more valuable
than the values that my my whole self is
are actually yearning for
that that's a piece that has to be done
let me throw in a tangible you know me i
like the tangible
you know to the you know the
introduction piece i said you know we
need to de-program
ourselves from status-oriented
consumption so if a person thinks they
need to have a fancy bmw
to be who they are and therefore they
have to take a high-pressure job with a
90-minute commute
so that they can afford this bmw the
result is they're not going to have the
time to spend with
their children or their spouse or their
friends and so they have
taken this ideology which programmed
into them by psychologically astute
media and advertising and have inserted
that
instead of their actual really
meaningful goals
yeah absolutely and you can see that
happening in all kinds of interesting
ways where for example
rather than you know hanging out with
friends and family
they go to a you know an upwardly mobile
business meeting with people that they
have
very little sense of actual connection
with because in the back of their mind
they don't even like the jobs they've
got right just you got this huge
explosion and what's interesting about
is if there's a
there's a synergy value that shows up
because
the way i'm describing it it's kind of
like freeing your mind
and increasing a capacity to make more
meaningful choices
but at the same time it's also freeing
your economy because if you're not
addicted to this particular vector of
status consumption you're obviously not
necessarily dependent on as much
of a flow of money and this gives you a
lot more actual freedom
exactly and you know at least to my mind
i strongly suspect that one of the
roads to getting ready for game b is to
get one's financial life in order
and that doesn't mean making more money
it may well mean just spending less
less less having your buttons pushed to
make you think you need
x y and z